A Guide to the Papers of Clifford Dowdey 1941-1967
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Clifford Dowdey 1941-1967
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
3809-c
This collection consists of 60 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was gifted to the University on 28 February 1969.
Biographical/Historical Information
Clifford Dowdey was a Virginia historian.
Scope and Content Information
Papers of Dowdey include business correspondence and contracts with several publishing companies for Dowdey's articles and books. Of interest is a series of letters, 1966, from Gerald E. Smith, Prentice-Hall, Inc. to Claire Smith re: Dowdey's appointment as editor of a book on Robert E. Lee for the "Great lives observed" series. In a letter, n.d., John C. Davis, Richmond, Va., writes to Dowdey arranging to hire Dowdey for the Civil War Centennial Tours in the spring of 1962.
Contents List
- Assignment of copyright from the Curtis Publishing Co. to Dowdey for "Sing For A Penny" 1941 Mar 25
- Assignment of copyright from McCall Corp. to Dowdey for "Ask No More" 1947 Oct 29
- Assignment of literary rights by Curtis Publishing Co. to Dowdey for "Affair With A Ghost" 1953 Nov 4
- Contract with Alfred A. Knopf, Inc. for "Lee At Gettysburg" 1957 Aug 1
- Agreement with Va. Civil War Comission to edit Lee's Wartime Dispatches 1959 Jun 12
- Contract with Little, Brown & Co. for "Lee's Last Campaign" 1958 Mar 10
- Contract with Little, Brown & Co. re: "The Seven Days" 1960 Jul 11
- Revised agreement with Doubleday & Co. re: Where the Last Rose Lingers1961 Dec 26
- General Correspondence 1961-1962
  9 items
- Contract with Little, Brown & Co. for "Biography of R.E. Lee" 1962 Jan 10
- Contract with Little, Brown & Co. for The Golden Age1963 Dec 2
- Correpondence and Contracts re: a reprint of Bugles Blow No More1965
  5 items
- General Correspondence, chiefly re: The Golden Age1963 Dec 2
  18 items
- Items re: Dowdey's possible editorship of a vol. on R.E. Lee 1966 Apr
  6 items
- General Correspondence 1966
- Reprint of an article on "Derwent" from The Ironworker1966
- Contract with Little, Brown & Co. for The Golden Age1967 Nov 16